Hello! In today's episode of Bug Bounty
Reports Explained, you will learn how
Frans Rosen was able to access millions of
files by bypassing AWS S3 signed URLs. The
vulnerability was rewarded $25,000. The write-up,
originally published at Detectify's blog,
is linked in the description. Detectify is also
a sponsor of today's video. It's a DAST scanner
powered by leading ethical hackers in the world.
Their payload-based testing finds undocumented
vulnerabilities from OWASP top 10, vulnerabilities
behind authentication, misconfigurations in CORS, S3
buckets, encryption and much more. Detectify
puts hacker knowledge into hands of security
engineers to fix their applications. Start a free,
2-week trial on detectify.com/bbre to see what
it finds on your website. AWS S3 is Amazon's
service used for storing files in the cloud.
When the application needs to show the user a file
that's stored there, the developer has at least
two options. Let's say it's an image. One
option is to basically stream the file
from the S3 through the server. But you can
probably tell that this is not the most optimal
solution. It adds latency and uses resources of
the server. It would be much better to let the
user download the file from S3 bucket directly.
However, how do you then make sure that users only
download their own files? If you make the bucket
public then there is no access control at all.
This issue can be solved using S3 signed URLs. It
works this way: a user wants to download a file
that's stored on s3 bucket. The server
generates a specific link for that user
that's only valid for a limited time and
for the one specified file. With that link,
the user can access the file from S3 bucket
directly. But what is that special in this link?
Among other parameters, this link contains a
signature. The signature is only valid for this
one file. If you try to access different one with
the same signature, it will not work. The same
goes for accessing a file after the expiration
period. The signature is generated on the backend.
To create it, the server uses a secret
key which, as the name strongly suggests,
is secret and not present in the link. It is 40
characters long and the signature uses SHA-256.
The brute-force of this would take ages, so for
sure we will not be able to generate our own
valid signature. We need to find
another way to hack this mechanism.
With such things, it's usually better to not
look for a vulnerability in AWS' mechanism
but in its implementations by developers.
We know that we won't break SHA-256,
but what if we would just ask the server to
create a link to a different file. For example
you can use path traversal to get a signed URL
to a file from completely different directory
that the developers wanted to allow. But the
problem is, even if we can read arbitrary file,
we don't know what files are stored there. We
would have to blindly brute-force file names which
would significantly reduce the impact. However,
if you could get a signature for a directory,
not a file, and the server would have ListObjects
permission, you could get directory listing.
And I know from experience that
some developers absolutely love
storing everything just in one bucket: receipts
and reports mixed with css and javascript files,
separated only by different directory. But
coming back to our undisclosed application.
There, you requested a file using s3_key with
the filename and random_key parameters. Then, the
application opened the URL with this random key in
the path which then redirected to the signed URL.
Why did they take this additional step? I
don't know but what i know for sure is that
s3_key was not validated at all. You could just
put the / there, follow the redirect and there
was directory listing of the whole bucket. And
inside... millions of files. Basically all of the
data was stored in this bucket. The hunter quickly
reported it and got $15,000 plus $10,000 of bonus.
To fix this, you mustn't store internal files
along with user files in the same bucket with
the same permissions, you must somehow separate
it. I think the main takeaway from this report is
that if something is signed or encrypted doesn't
automatically mean that it's secure. Anyway,
if you've learned something new today, leave a
like or leave a subscription. Also, sign up for
BBRE newsletter to get more tips and tricks.
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye!